<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://huaweicloud.github.io/xpanse-website/blog</id>
    <title>Open Services Cloud Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://huaweicloud.github.io/xpanse-website/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Open Services Cloud Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://huaweicloud.github.io/xpanse-website/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Services Cloud and GAIA-X, digital sovereignty]]></title>
        <id>https://huaweicloud.github.io/xpanse-website/blog/2022/07/20/gaiax</id>
        <link href="https://huaweicloud.github.io/xpanse-website/blog/2022/07/20/gaiax"/>
        <updated>2022-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As GAIA-X shapes data sovereignty, and Open Services Cloud frames technology sovereignty, both combined provides digital]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As GAIA-X shapes data sovereignty, and Open Services Cloud frames technology sovereignty, both combined provides digital
sovereignty.</p><p>In details, it means:</p><ul><li>GAIA-X focuses on portability of <strong>cloud data</strong></li><li>Open Services Cloud focuses on portability of <strong>cloud data processing services</strong> and also fulfills the Data Act's
requirements for cloud services portability</li><li>You need to have both portability of data and its associated data processing service to achieve digital sovereignty.
One without the other has limited value.</li><li>We implement GAIA-X data portability as services on top of Open Services Cloud to bring together these two
features, **data portability and data processing portability££.</li></ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>JB Onofré</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/jbonofre</uri>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Bryan Che</name>
            <uri>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryanche/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="gaia-x" term="gaia-x"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to Open Services Cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://huaweicloud.github.io/xpanse-website/blog/2022/07/14/introduction</id>
        <link href="https://huaweicloud.github.io/xpanse-website/blog/2022/07/14/introduction"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Eclipse Open Services Cloud.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Eclipse Open Services Cloud.</p><p>Today, the ecosystem is being locked out of public clouds. Only the cloud providers can create native managed services.
The consequence is that it's pretty hard to integrate 3rd party SaaS islands.</p><p>On the other hand, the enterprises fear lock-in. There's no real service portability between different clouds.</p><p>And even worse, cloud data is the ultimate lock-out and lock-in. The data lock-out means cloud data storage software is
inefficient compare to cloud data storage service. Even if we can have a software storage on a purchased virtual
machine, it's inefficient and expensive compared to native cloud storage services.
The data lock-in is because the cloud data is tightly coupled to prorprietary cloud services. It's hard to
extract/export raw data from one cloud to another. Even if cloud data can be exported, it's not really useful without
the accompanying cloud service.</p><p>Open Services Cloud solves:</p><ul><li><strong>federated</strong>: the goal is to create an open services ecosystem that works across different clouds. Open Services
Cloud solves ecosystem lockout &amp; lack of service portability.</li><li><strong>open</strong>: the purpose is to enable customers to choose the services and providers of their choice. Thanks to that, we
avoid customer lock-in.</li><li><strong>data infrastructure based on European values</strong>: Open Services Cloud enables European cloud providers and ecosystems
to meet the needs of Europeans. Open Services Cloud open up the market, avoiding the hyperscalers to control and set
the market for cloud and data services in Europe.</li></ul><p>Open Services Cloud is a Open Source initiative reshaping the cloud market.</p><p>Welcome to Open Services Cloud!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>JB Onofré</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/jbonofre</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="introduction" term="introduction"/>
    </entry>
</feed>